technotraits.com 2013-03-24

# Privacy Policy

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

Technotraits.com may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

**Information we gather and track**

The type of personal information we collect are:

  * Name (Comments)
  * Website URl (optional) (Comments)
  * Email address (Comments)
  * Google AdSense that stores tracking cookies on your computer
  * 3rd party advertisements that may store tracking cookies on your computer to recognize repeated visits (only)
  * Tracking cookies by Google Analytics for statistical purposes – this data is not traceable back to you except for your IP address

**How we use Cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

Technotraits.com may use cookies to keep some information that are placed by a Web site in a storage place on your own computer. We use cookies to track usage patterns on the site. Our cookies do not contain personally identifiable information and such cookies are not shared with any third party.

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. As a result of your visit to our site, ad server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**How we use Collected Information**

The name and website URl are displayed on comments, but email address is secure with us. We do not share it with outside parties. Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

**How to Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an email at contact{at}technotraits.com.
